# **Dmytro Snisarenko**

## Software Engineer

Last update: October 4, 2022

Up-to-date version of CV is available at

https://sneas.github.io/cv/



I'm a full-stack developer with more than 15 years of experience. The setup for my last three projects happens to be AWS / Serverless / Lambda / NodeJS / Typescript for the backend, Angular / React / VanillaJS / WebComponents for the front end, Cypress / Jest / Endtest for testing, and CI/CD / Terraform for ongoing automation.

# **Professional Experience**

Nov 2021 - Present

### Vocably, Weesp, NL

Founder, Software Engineer

<u>Vocably</u> is a platform (extension and an app) that helps users to look up new words while surfing the web and study those words as flashcards on mobile.

As a founder and the only developer of Vocably, I'm responsible for:

- · Developing backend with AWS / GCP / Lambda / API Gateway / Cognito
- · Developing frontend/mobile experience (PWA) with Angular / Amplify
- Developing Chrome Extension with Vanilla / Web Components
- DevOps with CircleCl / Terraform / NodeJS / Zx / Bash
- Testing with Jest / Cypress / Endtest.io
- · Market analysis, product marketing, cost and pricing analysis



Feb 2021 - Nov 2021

### Athyria, Seattle, USA

Software Engineer

Completed two projects for John Deere.

- 1. A system that receives, stores, and processes operation metrics from different types of vehicles. Mainly AWS, Terraform, DynamoDB, Lambda
- 2. A sales tool that helps users to track, analyze, and predict various machinery metrics. Mainly Angular, OAuth, AWS, Terraform



Jul 2019 - Jan 2021

### DAZN, Amsterdam, NL

Platform Engineer

High load media streaming platform.

Started as a front-end engineer at My Account team. Later as a full-stack/dev-ops engineer for the Developer Experience team which provided development, deployment, and automation tools for more than 60 teams and 500 people across DAZN Engineering.

#### Responsibilities:

- · Develop and maintain "My Account" section of the website (front end)
- Develop and maintain various deployment and development tools (full stack)



Reference: Cirpo Cinelly, Engineering Manager

Feb 2017 - Jun 2019

### KLM Royal Dutch Airlines, Schiphol, NL

Senior Frontend Developer

Real time fault tolerant mobile application used by 330 KLM mechanics at Schiphol airport to perform between-the-flight aircraft maintenance. The application displays up-to-date KLM's fleet schedule and towing information, helps team leaders to manage teams, and provides the scope of work for mechanics.

#### Responsibilities:

· Incorporate business requirements into biweekly product increments

#### Achievements:

- · As a scrum team member, developed and launched a mobile app from the scratch
- Open source library as a solution to common Ionic's problem. 1k weekly downloads in 2020



Reference: Önder Ceylan, Tech Lead

Jun 2014 - Feb 2017

### Knab hypotheek, Amsterdam, NL

Senior Frontend Developer

Core front end developer of a fully automated mortgage advice system.

Started as a backend developer and eventually transferred to the frontend.

#### Responsibilities:

- · Developed new functionality
- · Conducted job interviews

#### Achievements:

- · Developed flexible registration process and 16 tools intended to gather detailed customer's legal and financial data
- · Component library as a result of collaboration with the design team
- · Introduced test driven development process with Karma and test automation with Protractor



Reference: Mark Sizoo, Tech Lead

### upwork.com, Mountain View, USA

Senior Frontend Developer

Core frontend developer of the world's #1 freelance marketplace.

#### Responsibilities:

- · Developed A/B tested functionality for company's crucial business component: Job Posting Engine
- · Conducted job interviews
- · Facilitated onboarding process

#### Achievements:

- · Developed and successfully launched job post engine: highly-configured job posting and rendering tool
- Introduced test driven development process into the organization's development flow



Reference: Sean Kane, Vice President of Engineering

# **Career insights**

#### 2010 - 2012

Full stack freelancer (PHP, JS, SQL, Linux, CI/CD).

Successfully completed multiple small and middle-sized projects. Received <u>positive feedback</u> from all of my clients. Reviews are available <u>here</u>. Must be registered user to read all the reviews. Sorry.

#### 2005 - 2010

Junior/middle full-stack developer (PHP, JS, SQL, Linux).

Significant experience was acquired while working on <a href="GameWatcher">GameWatcher</a> and <a href="RecordNerd.com">RecordNerd.com</a>.

#### 2000 - 2003

Worked as visual designer for a local TV channel. Acquired passion for objects composition, color matching and animation.

### **Education**

Masters degree in Computer Engineering. Sevastopol State Technical University [2002 – 2007]

### Certifications

- aws AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate Jan 18, 2019
- C Professional Scrum Master I Apr 2, 2018
- React Nanodegree Dec 27, 2017
- PHP 5.3 Jan 24, 2011

# Additional experience

- Some of my interests and hobbies revolve around GitHub and open source community.
  A complete list of side/hobby projects: <a href="https://github.com/sneas">https://github.com/sneas</a>
- (Not so)Active member of developer communities
  - toster.ru/user/search (Russian speaking community)
  - stackoverflow.com/users/379949/sneas
  - <u>ru.stackoverflow.com/users/272582/sneas</u> (Russian speaking community)

Categories: Javascript Angular React Typescript